GABRIELLA DE FRANCESCO

425-241-0958 | Washington, D.C. | gabriella.defrancesco@outlook.com | www.linkedin.com/in/gabriella-m-defrancesco/

Profile

Full-stack software engineer skilled in Git, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, Django, Node, Express, React, MongoDB, SQL, problem-solving, planning, modeling, and maintaining applications with client-API architectures. Experience working in teams and independently to build functioning sites that solve real-world business problems.

Skills

Front-End

HTML5 / CSS 3 Bootstrap JavaScript / ES6+ jQuery React Git/GitHub

Back-End

Python Node.js Express MongoDB / Mongoose PostgreSQL

Relevant Experience

Software Engineering Immersive

03/2019 - 06/2019

General Assembly, Washington, DC

Completed a 12-week, 480 hour immersive course applying full-stack software engineering skills to group and individual projects including:

- Developed an interactive memory game using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- Built and deployed a JSON API, with RESTful routes and CRUD functionality allowing users to traverse data about every country around the globe including the national flag, currency, languages and population statistics.
- Developed a full-stack app in collaboration with a team using GitHub and Slack. Technologies included MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, React, CSS, and Node. Responsibilities included creating components and routes on the frontend, developing wireframes, CSS styling, and deploying the application with Heroku.
- Created an app that allows users to identify and save favorite inspirational quotes. Built a custom API and using React, MongoDB, Express, and Node. Next step is incorporating responsive web principles.
- Designed a full-stack e-commerce website built

Relevant Experience

with MongoDB, Express, Node, and Embedded JavaScript with mapping through MapBox and image uploading functionality through Cloudinary.

Software Trainer

06/2013 - 10/2013

ScribesSTAT, Bellingham, WA

- Completed intensive training and developed software knowledge.
- Coached medical professionals using electronic health records (EHR) on the floor.
- Guided users to resolve issues, by reviewing documentation.

Work History

English Tutor

07/2019 - 03/2019

Self-Employed, Fairfax, VA

- Tutored international high school students in English, SAT, AP courses and other subjects focusing on STEM.
- Prepared students for Reading, Writing & Language, and Essay sections of the SAT and the English, Reading, and Essay sections of the ACT

Care Manager

02/2017 - 10/2018

Aegis Living, Bellevue, WA

- Oversaw facility with 100 residents receiving memory care, short-term care or assisted living and trained 8 new hires.
- Documented observations of resident behavior, complaints, or physical symptoms to nurses.

Administrative Assistant

02/2016 - 12/2017

Wave Broadband, Kirkland, WA

- Provided administrative assistance to 400+ employees and wrote company-wide email announcements.
- Worked independently on special non-recurring and ongoing projects for the Human Resources Department.

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Creative Writing

12/2015

Western Washington University, Bellingham, WA

- 3.5 GPA
- Minor in Psychology
- · Coursework in Technical Writing & Editing